- Synced and corrected by Firefly -
- www.addic7ed.com -
[GPS SIGNAL BEEPING]
Come on. Piece of shit.
[BEEPS]
Signal keeps getting dropped.
EDDIE: I hate being
this far in at night.
I'd be sweating too if the law
caught me fishing with this.
[SIGNAL BEEPING]
- JONES: Oh. I got it. Got it.
- [KEYBOARD KEYS CLACKING]
Looks like the last drop zone is...
Just beyond these trees.
[SIGNAL BEEPS STEADILY]
[BEEPING INTENSIFIES]
Hey, hey, stop.
I think we're here, boys.
BLAINE: Sure about this, Eddie?
Man said bring out three boxes
and drop 'em that's all I know.
BLAINE: All right.
[MOTOR SPUTTERS AND STOPS]
What just happened?
It won't start.
BLAINE: What the hell
you mean it won't start?
It won't start.
[LOUD THUD]
That... that was just a gator, right?
- [LOUD THUDDING]
- [GRUNTING]
[EXCLAIMING IN FEAR]
Shit!
[PANTING]
Son of a bitch!
What the fuck is that?
[GASPS]
[MUFFLED SCREAMING]
JONES: Where'd he go?
[GASPING]
- Come on!
- I got you. Just swim.
- Please! Please! Please!
- JONES: Come on!
Just swim to me. Swim to me.
Come on, man!
Just come here!
Swim to me, man!
[GASPS]
- Shit!
- Where'd he go?
EDDIE: Blaine!
[ROOTS CREAKING]
Listen. Listen.
EDDIE: What?
[ROOTS CONTINUE CREAKING]
Oh, shit!
- Shit! Shit! Shit!
- [LIGHTER CLICKING]
[EXPLOSION]
[SCREECHING]
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
[CHITTERING]
Shit!
- [ROARING]
- [BOTH GRUNTING]
[YELLS]
[GAGGING]
[GRUNTS]
[PANTING]
[THEME MUSIC PLAYING]
♪ Swamp Thing 1x01 ♪
Pilot
KAREN: Who was trapped in the castle?
- ALL: Princess Cassie.
- KAREN: Princess Cassie.
- And who was angry with her?
- _
- ALL: The Giant King.
The Giant King.
Now, why was The Giant King angry, guys?
ALL: They stole all his gold.
KAREN: Because they
stole all of his gold.
But Princess Cassie
was in there by herself.
- [COUGHING]
- So, do you think she was happy?
- ALL: No.
- KAREN: Excited?
ALL: No.
- KAREN: How did she feel?
- ALL: Afraid.
KAREN: She's scared...
She's very scared.
When you're scared, what
are you supposed to do?
[INDISTINCT AND MUFFLED CHATTER]
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
[WHIMPERING]
[BODY THUDS]
[PANTING]
Oh, my God. Susie! Susie!
_
- [BOY SPEAKING FRENCH]
- [MAN SHOUTS]
[MAN IN ENGLISH] Hey, put that down!
[SPEAKING FRENCH]
[MAN IN ENGLISH] Stop! Put it down!
Hey... Stop! Stop!
[SPEAKING FRENCH]
[MAN IN ENGLISH] Hey, now.
I'm trying to help you.
Put it down! Put it down.
Doctor, hey, don't!
- [SPEAKS FRENCH]
- [IN ENGLISH] Don't take your mask off!
[BOY CONTINUES SHOUTING IN FRENCH]
[IN FRENCH] _
_
[HELICOPTER HOVERING]
Okay. Go ahead. Say it.
What, that you were great?
That you're a hero?
Oh! I thought for sure
you were gonna tear into me
for risking hemorrhagic
fever for that girl.
It saved her life.
Plus, I know you're gonna beat
yourself up over that later
so just please...
I'll go through all
the tests. Don't worry.
Thank you.
And we dropped the last of the
antibiotics and the test kits
in the village in case
the water goes south again.
What would I do without you, Harlan?
- Work on finding us boyfriends?
- No.
[LAUGHS]
Okay. Well, if you're
not gonna do that...
Uh, Atlanta called earlier.
There's a possible situation
brewing back in the States.
Where?
Ah...
You're kidding.
_
Well, it's not the Congo.
You want to make a left there.
You still remember.
How long has it been
since you were home?
A while.
Well, somebody forgot
to tell beautiful Marais
that 1962 was a long time ago.
[MUFFLED LAUGHTER]
DR. CHOWODURY: I'm glad the CDC is here
'cause I'm running out of options.
So, it's still just the three infected?
Fourth came in this morning.
Little girl presented first.
She had direct contact with her
teacher and the school nurse.
- And today's patient?
- A clerk.
From the Sunderland One Stop on Guidry.
Shit. It's spreading.
Yeah.
They all here?
[CLEARS THROAT] Okay, everyone.
For those of you who don't know
my name is Dr. Abby Arcane
with the CDC's Epidemic
Intelligence Service.
That is a real thing.
Um, my team is here to assist
in caring for your patients
and to find the source of this disease.
We need fresh blood samples
and diaries of each patient's contacts
before presenting symptoms.
If we can identify the disease,
we can figure out how to treat it.
For now though, it is
masks, gloves and goggles
for anyone in direct
contact with the patients.
Caregivers do not get
sick on my watch, okay?
Let's get to it.
- ABBY: Hey, sweetie.
- [INHALES SHARPLY]
How you feelin'?
So I found this on her pillow.
Maybe transfer from the ambulance?
I don't think so.
Has she been breathing like
this since she was admitted?
Our X-rays did find a
stubborn mycosis in her lungs
but it's not fungal.
I'll have the staff
check for contamination.
Excuse me?
- You can't take those.
- I'm not.
- You're not what?
- Taking them.
I'm just looking as an interested party.
Are these blood tests,
are they the most recent?
Okay.
If you can give me the tests
from when she first came in
I can compare them
with the latest results.
Who are you exactly?
I told you before,
this area is off limits.
- Fuck, again.
- I'm sorry, Dr. Arcane.
Listen, you're not gonna
find anything you need
in the standard CDC rule book.
- I promise.
- Excuse me.
- Get security!
- No, no, no. It's fine.
- It's fine. It's fine.
- Let's go.
I'm out. I'm gone. I'm out.
You're gonna wanna speak
to me sooner or later.
Hey, can we just be friends?
- See you tomorrow, Bob.
- [DOOR OPENS]
Who the hell was that?
No idea. We should find out though.
- Uh, where are we on Susie's parents?
- Mother's dead.
Her father Eddie's MIA.
Cops say his boat's not in his slip
so he could be out in the water.
ABBY: Mmm.
And the school bus
picked her up as usual.
So maybe Dad made it home.
[CROWS CAWING]
[VEHICLE APPROACHING]
- Matt?
- Dispatch said
a Dr. Arcane requested assistance.
I said that was fucking impossible.
- You're a cop now.
- Yeah, four years.
Jesus Christ, Abby. Didn't
think we'd ever see you again.
I wish it was under
better circumstances.
Yeah.
- The Coyle girl. How's she doing?
- Not good.
And right now, she's patient zero.
What do you know about her dad?
- Who, Eddie?
- Yeah.
He's a fisherman, mostly.
Pulled him in a few times
for game violations, a DUI...
ABBY: Child Services?
MATT: Never had any complaints.
Well, around here, that
makes you Father of the Year.
[MATT CHUCKLES]
When the little girl got
sick, we called, but no answer.
And since Eddie's boat was still out
we didn't think anything of it.
[DOOR CREAKS]
Mr. Coyle?
Coyle!
[FLIES BUZZING]
[WOOD SCRAPING]
- Matt?
- Yeah, I hear it.
[WOOD SCRAPING]
Mr. Coyle?
MATT: Oh, my God.
[WOOD SCRAPING]
Mr. Coyle?
Coyle!
[GUN CLICKS]
[DOOR CREAKING]
[WOOD SCRAPING]
Hey.
- Hey!
- [SHRIEKS]
- Fuck!
- Drop it, right now!
- What?
- I said drop it!
Wait, hold up...
- Drop it!
- I'm collecting a sample!
I'm collecting a sample!
What the hell are you doing here?
- You know this guy?
- Yeah. He was at the hospital earlier
- trespassing.
- Guys. Guys!
[PANTING]
You're focusing on the wrong thing here.
MATT: What the fuck?
- [CRACKS]
- [GASPS]
MATT: His name's Alec Holland.
Seen him around the past few months.
Some kind of, I don't
know, scientist-type.
- ABBY: Seriously?
- What?
You're not arresting him, are you?
He did break in.
Well, what happened with Eddie
Coyle wasn't because of him.
So what the hell did this?
It's what I intend to find out.
That's enough. No more.
Hey.
Excuse me, uh...
[CLEARS THROAT] Dr. Arcane,
can I talk to you for... Again?
- What is up with you?
- What?
- You're clearly not a local.
- No, I, uh...
I'm just trying to help.
By being everywhere you shouldn't be?
Listen, um, you saw the body.
Dealt with anything like that before?
We have it under control. It's okay.
Well, nothing's working, is it?
Pyrazinamide? Ethambutol?
Who are you again?
Holland, like, the country.
Listen. Listen, listen, listen.
Avery Sunderland hired me to
collect and analyze biological...
Congratulations. He's a very
important man around here.
Thank you very much. The thing is
is that I've been finding
some serious fucking crazy.
- Crazy?
- Yes, as in
biological processes
I've never seen before
and I think that they could
be connected to your infection.
How?
[SIGHS]
It's easier to show
you than to tell you.
Sunderland's lab's on
the water, 20 minutes out.
- I have patients waiting.
- Yes. Yes.
I know they're waiting.
They're waiting for a cure
but I'm guessing the
doctors haven't had any luck
ID'ing the pathogen yet.
No.
You like mysteries?
You know, old mystery, like
Murder She Wrote, Columbo...
- [LAUGHS] What?
- What?
Wow. I like references that
aren't from the 1980s...
It was the first thing that popped
in my... It doesn't have to...
- Well, no. I don't like mysteries...
- Okay.
- I like solutions.
- Me, too.
So let me help you find one, okay?
Okay? Going back to the hospital,
spinning around, trying
to find an answer...
It's not gonna get you
any closer to the truth.
But going out there
that will.
- Okay.
That worked, yeah.
That worked. Here we go.
[FLAPPING]
How'd you know I wasn't a local?
You're wearing designer flip-flops.
Comfy suckers, though.
And the attitude.
It's a bit of a giveaway, too.
ALEC: Watch your step.
It's tight.
- [DOG BARKING]
- Where is he?
Oh! What were you doing?
What were you doing? Come on.
It's a little steep, be careful.
ABBY: Aw!
This is my, uh, buddy, Garou.
[DOOR CLOSES]
What kind of study is this?
It's the kind dip-shit
biologists like me dream about.
Check this out.
All right, um...
How much do you know about mutagens?
The stuff that causes cancer,
that blows holes in human DNA...
Right. The ones we know about.
- Uh-huh.
- Right?
[BEEPING]
[DEVICE WHIRRING]
I'm close to identifying
an entirely new strand
buried deep in this swamp.
All right, here we go.
So, um, for the last seven months
I've been out on the water
mapping out biological hotspots
where the mutagenic
activity is the strongest
and the thing is, is that
for the last two weeks
I've noticed a steady increase
in speed of these processes.
- [BEEPS]
- And this...
is a sample I took just yesterday, um
at one of the most active sites.
This clear shit on top,
that's just swamp water, right?
But right there on the
bottom, you see that?
I do.
That doesn't belong.
ALEC: Green Spanish moss.
ABBY: Plant-based growth medium.
I've taken a few classes.
- You ready?
- Mmm-hmm.
[RUSTLING]
[CRACKLES]
Oh, my God.
- [GLASS CRACKLING]
- Holland!
- Fuck! Stop!
- [STEAM HISSES]
- What just happened?
- Fuck.
I don't know, um...
[KEYS CLACKING]
I think the stuff at the bottom
of the tube, I don't... I...
It's gotta be some sort of
biological accelerant or something.
- Like a fertilizer.
- Yeah.
But it only jacks up mutagens.
What?
You wanted to test Susie
Coyle's blood from two days ago
against today's to
see if it had changed.
Yes.
This really could be
what's making people sick.
It's like Columbo.
[CELL PHONE BUZZING]
All right, Coyle's body
is ready for postmortem.
Tell me, please, that you have
all this science fiction backed up.
- A hard-drive away.
- Okay.
- Can you get me to the hospital?
Might not let me in, but...
[INDISTINCT CHATTERING]
- RILEY: People.
- [INDISTINCT CHATTER]
Settle down, people. Settle down.
I know this bug has got everyone rattled
but the doctors are
doing everything they can.
MAN 1: Big timber's coming in
dumping their trash, burning trees...
The swamp puts food on our tables.
We lose that, we lose everything!
[INDISTINCT SHOUTING]
Just say it, Riley!
The swamp's had enough. This is payback.
WOMAN: Yeah!
RILEY: We... We don't
know what this is yet.
The hospital is on it 24/7, and the CDC.
MAN 2: Bullshit.
AVERY: Hold on! Hold on!
I'm not saying you're wrong,
but right now, let the
doctors do their work.
Hell, Avery, I don't
got money for doctors.
[INDISTINCT CHATTER]
It comes to that, you see me.
Goes for all of you.
You know that.
Maybe you ought to put some of
that Sunderland money into this town
and less in that nonsense lab of yours.
[ALL CLAMORING]
You know, the swamp
took my father from me
when I was still a boy.
You know that, right?
But ever since, that same swamp
has given me, you, and
this whole damn town
a way of life.
Yeah, there's something
special about this place
you know that, we all know that.
And you live here long
enough, you feel it
in your bones.
Now, my research
is about the future
uncovering what else
the swamp can offer.
New medicines, fertilizers,
God knows what else.
And if what we find is
worth what I hope it is
that could be the answer
to this town's troubles.
Your troubles, more like it.
A rising tide lifts all boats, Leon
even that shit box of yours.
[CROWD LAUGHS]
Hell, yeah, I took a hit and we all did.
ALL: Yeah.
I could have pulled up stakes
and left Marais high and dry.
But Marais is home.
Where my daddy is buried.
And my little girl.
Where I met Maria.
Now, if I was like most of you
and 20 years younger, I'd
get my ass back to work.
[CROWD LAUGHS]
[LAUGHS] All right, folks, listen.
We'll, uh, post updates
as we get 'em. Thank you.
[INDISTINCT CHATTERING]
ALEC: Excuse me.
AVERY: Of course.
That was a nice speech.
What are you doing here, Holland?
Did you get 'em?
Did you get the findings
I sent you last night?
I did, and I was wondering why
since I dismissed you two weeks ago.
Is that what that was?
Well, I assumed you'd reconsider
since things were just
getting interesting.
[AVERY SIGHS]
Say what you came to say.
For the last two weeks, the
evolutionary cycle of the mutagen
has just continued to skyrocket
and now out of nowhere,
people are just getting sick?
And you think there's a connection?
Yeah, I mean, yeah. I mean,
I can't rule it out. Yes.
You don't need to set your
hair on fire either, Holland.
I'm not a scientist
but disease is not
uncommon around Marais.
We had an epidemic in '86
and one in '92.
People get sick. They always have.
Yeah, sure. That makes sense.
- But you're not convinced.
- No, I'm not, Avery.
You, uh... You hired me to
follow the science and here I am.
I also hired a man looking
for a second chance.
This town doesn't need a panic.
It doesn't need an
epidemic either, Avery.
MARIA: Honey, Mr.
Adams would like a word.
Oh, boy. Aye-aye!
Go home, Holland. We got it from here.
Okay.
[DOOR CLOSES]
- ALEC: Hey.
- Hey.
Okay.
Do you ever sleep, Dr. Arcane?
Not when everyone else does.
And it's Abby.
Have you ever seen an autopsy?
Yeah, yeah.
Saw an alien autopsy once.
Pretty sure it was fake though.
All right.
I'm, uh, gonna set up the test gear.
You kids have fun.
How's the girl?
The drug therapy is slowing
the beast in the adults, but...
Susie had gone for two days
before we got to her, so...
She's also only nine years old.
It's not your fault.
A plant sample, straight from
the source. Knock yourself out.
Thank you.
[CLEARS THROAT]
Got a reaction here.
[MONITOR BEEPING]
- [GASPS]
- [BEEPING INTENSIFIES]
[GROWLS]
[SCREAMING]
[METAL CLANKING]
We gotta go. We gotta go.
[ABBY SCREAMS]
Come on. Come on. Come on. Come on.
[MACHINE BEEPING]
ABBY: Oh, my God!
Alec!
[MACHINE BEEPING RAPIDLY]
[ELECTRICITY CRACKLING]
Fuck!
ALEC: Come on! Come on! Come on!
[ABBY AND ALEC SCREAM]
[SCREAMING]
[SHRIEKING]
[GASPS] Susie.
Daddy!
Abby! Abby, wait!
[ELECTRICITY CRACKLING]
Go, go, go, go!
Susie. Susie.
[GASPS]
[OBJECTS CLATTERING]
[SNARLING AND CHITTERING]
Clear! Clear! Clear!
She's Code Blue.
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
Come on, honey.
Come on.
[GASPS]
Susie.
Okay, I'm getting
something. Restart the IV.
[INDISTINCT RADIO CHATTER]
[SIGHS]
You all right?
You have a, uh...
It's a piece of glass.
[SIGHS]
So what now?
We can't just sit here.
[CELL PHONE BUZZING]
I'm gonna go check something out.
You coming?
Does it involve bourbon?
Actually, yes.
[COUNTRY MUSIC PLAYING ON SPEAKERS]
[EXCITED CHATTERING]
ALEC: What?
I was just kidding
about the, uh, bourbon.
A friend of mine's inside.
She's a reporter.
Maybe she knows why Eddie
was out in that water.
ALEC: This is where you
used to hang out, huh?
ABBY: This is where
everybody in Marais hangs out.
Scary woman, 12 o'clock.
Xanadu.
Can't believe she's still here.
[INDISTINCT CHATTER]
Abby Arcane.
Goddamn!
[CHUCKLES]
- I heard you were back in town.
- [BOTH CHUCKLE]
Liz.
Delroy's on a supply run,
but I know he'd wanna see you.
Uh, yeah, I'd love to see
your dad, but it's, uh...
It's not that kind of visit.
Right.
Guess it'd take nothing
less than a medical meltdown
to bring you back to Marais.
Uh, Alec Holland,
- this is Liz Tremayne.
- Hi.
I...
Yeah, you guys catch
up, I'll get the drink.
What's with Sandals?
He's all right.
So...
Heard you found something
seriously messed up
over at Eddie Coyle's.
Who said that?
It's out there, Abby.
[SCOFFS] This town...
You still work for the Echo, right?
I need a favor.
[CHUCKLES SOFTLY]
I gotta write the Coyle
story before I can hold it.
I'm not saying that, I just, um...
Have you seen anything
unusual at the docks lately?
Wait, you're Abby's reporter?
For the Marais Echo Weekly.
- ALEC: Hmm.
- Emphasis on the weekly.
So I have time to help
out my dad when I can.
- No offense.
- Some taken.
Not a lot of people are talking, Abby.
So you already know it's bad.
Why do you say that?
'Cause it's Marais.
Mosquitoes and gossip...
Two things we get a lot of here.
But...
I have heard whispers
of someone hiring boats
to go out into the swamp at night.
Who?
No one knows. The who or the why.
- And Eddie Coyle?
- His boat was never found.
And the guy he crewed
with, he's AWOL, too.
Last thing anyone heard
they were headed out to Skeeter Cove.
Oh, shit.
Abby...
No. Sit.
Could you give us a moment, please?
[INAUDIBLE]
- LIZ: Can I get you anything?
- MARIA: No, thanks.
Five thousand people work
at the CDC. I looked it up.
That's 4,999 other options
they could have sent.
I'm good at my job.
They knew I could help.
I wanted to help.
Where did you end up studying?
Emory.
Okay. So, let's think about
this just for a minute.
Your freshman year...
When you were going out to parties...
- I didn't...
- When you were going out to parties...
I spent your freshman
year in Shawna's bedroom.
Mrs. Sunderland...
I think about Shawna every day.
I'm speaking now.
Sophomore year...
Maybe that's just about
the time you figured out
what you wanted to do in life
and declared a major.
That's about the time I...
stumbled out of her
bed and into a bottle.
A lot of bottles.
Now, what I'm really trying to forget
is your senior year.
Because while you were
applying to medical schools
my husband was talking
to divorce lawyers.
It was the thought of losing him
that finally made me quit drinking.
And I asked Avery
where that kind of strength came from.
And he said
because...
all that darkness wasn't my fault.
It was yours.
You said you're good at what you do
and that you can help,
that's why you came here.
And that's why I'm letting you stay.
But if that little girl dies...
She won't.
Promise me.
[SCOFFS]
Go ahead. Promise.
[EXHALES SHARPLY]
[SNIFFLES]
I promise.
Hmm.
Within the minute she's better
I want you gone.
[EXHALES]
[SNIFFLES]
We... We should go
check out Skeeter Cove.
Okay.
[THUNDER CRASHES]
[THUNDER RUMBLING]
ABBY: Oh, my God.
ALEC: What the hell?
How is that even possible?
ALEC: I have no idea.
[THUNDER RUMBLING]
ALEC: Found something.
Laptop.
ALEC: That could help.
Here, hold this.
What is it?
[RATTLING]
[THUNDER RUMBLING]
ALEC: It's like a...
Underwater release
mechanism or something.
Releasing what?
I don't know.
Let's take it back to the lab.
[THUNDER RUMBLING]
- [KEYBOARD CLACKING]
- Let's see what you are.
- [SWITCH CLICKS]
- [BEEPS]
It's almost worth
coming back just for him.
What are you doing, buggin' her?
Come here. [CLICKS TONGUE]
Go downstairs.
[SIGHS]
- Thank you.
- Yeah.
And now, we wait. [SIGHS]
So, is, uh, Mrs. Sunderland the
reason you don't visit home much?
Uh...
She'd say I'm the reason
I don't come home much.
And she's right.
Do you ever feel like that?
That's why I'm here.
One thing we have in common.
[ALEC SCOFFS]
May I offer you a drink?
I sure as hell could use one.
That's two things we have in common.
Okay.
[GRUNTS] Let's see.
Hmm...
- Glasses...
- It's... It's okay.
Okay.
Here you go.
[BOTH SIGH]
I...
have a confession.
You're the president of
the Columbo fan page.
[LAUGHS]
No. No, I...
I Googled you.
Oh.
When?
Earlier today.
Yeah. Yeah, it's funny you
think I haven't seen those.
- I'm sorry.
- No. No. It's fine.
[CLEARS THROAT]
So, it's true?
What?
That I, uh, manipulated the data
to better prove my conclusion?
Yeah. Yeah.
I still stand by what I found.
But you couldn't replicate the results.
Not yet.
Okay. So, why do it then?
Why do it then?
Yeah, um... Can I have that?
I don't know. No, I know. Um...
I always wanted to be known by my work
you know, I wanted the
work to define me and, uh...
Well, now it does, just
not in the way I wanted.
So, how did all that land you here?
Oh, in this palace?
- [CHUCKLES]
- Uh...
Well, when the smoke cleared,
I realized pretty quickly
that I was chasing after
the wrong things, you know.
I don't...
need to be published in the big journals
or, uh, [CLEARS THROAT]
taught in high school biology classes
although that would
be pretty cool, but...
No. Uh...
The joy's always been in the discovery.
So...
Guess sometimes the mistakes
we make stay with us.
What I wouldn't give for you to
Google my name, and it'd just say...
"Sorry, your query got back no results."
Hmm.
Well, look at that
it's three things we have in common.
Oh.
What? What do you mean?
Speaking of Avery Sunderland...
[SIGHS] Um...
He and his wife had a daughter...
Shawna.
And, um...
Growing up, we were...
We were best friends.
She was like my sister.
The Sunderlands were...
They were, uh... [CHUCKLES]
They were like parents to me.
And two days before we graduated
I, um...
[BEEPS]
[WHIRRING]
Right. Let's grab that.
No... [STAMMERS]
Sorry. I mean, two nights
before you graduated...
What?
[SCOFFS]
I killed her.
[SNIFFLES]
Let's check that result.
- Oh yeah.
- Let's get those results.
- [SNIFFLES]
- Shit.
What?
This stuff in the box, it's
a biological accelerant.
It's like the stuff we
pulled from the swamp.
Like, it's times...
A lot.
So, someone's dumping it here?
Okay. Pull some samples I
can take back to the hospital.
What, you think that could help?
I mean, I think if this is
what's turning our pathogen
into what's making people sick
maybe there's a way we
can slow the infection.
Susie and the others
aren't going to wait.
All right.
All the samples are here.
And you'll know what you
need better than I do.
So, I'm gonna...
- Where are you going?
- The laptop that we found on the boat
this thing is showing
these GPS locations
and I'm thinking
that they're markings where other
accelerant boxes have been dumped.
So...
I'm gonna fish 'em out
before other people get sick.
Good. Good. Yeah. I'll
see you at the hospital.
You okay?
Yeah.
[SNIFFLES]
[DOOR OPENS]
Abby...
Why'd you Google me?
I'm sorry, but your
query got back no results.
That was pretty good.
[DEVICE BEEPING]
[BEEPING INTENSIFIES]
[BEEPING STOPS]
ABBY: Listen, I think
I may have something
that could help us get
a handle on this disease.
HARLAN: We could use anything you got.
This drug regimen slowed this
thing, but it hasn't stopped it.
What do you need from me?
I need access to the hospital's lab
and time to go through
some new findings.
You bet. I'll get on it.
Thank you, Harlan.
[BEEPING]
[BEEPING STOPS]
Hello?
- Can I help...
- [GUNSHOTS]
[GROANS]
[GRUNTS]
[DISTANT EXPLOSION]
[DOG BARKING]
[ENGINE REVVING]
[GASPS]
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
[GROANING]
[COUGHS]
[GASPING]
[VINES RUSTLING]
Alec!
[VINES CREAKING]
Oh, my God.
Alec!
[RUSTLING]
[METAL SQUEAKING]
- [FAINT THUDDING]
- [SQUEAKING CONTINUES]
[GASPING]
[THUDDING CONTINUES]
[SCREAMING]
[CONTINUES SCREAMING]
[CREATURE SNARLING]
[ABBY WHIMPERING]
[SCREAMS]
[GASPS]
- Synced and corrected by Firefly -
- www.addic7ed.com -
[THEME MUSIC PLAYING]